VANESSA FORD

STRENGTHS

🛧 Analytical Thinker

Excelled at providing analytical insights and practical solutions in my previous role, leading to improvements in decision-making procedures.

Proactive

Proactively took on additional responsibility as team lead, managing and coordinating multiple projects simultaneously with successful outcomes.

Extensive experience manipulating data using SQL to uncover actionable insights, improve processes and drive business qoals

SKILLS

Azure DevOps · Jira · SQL · Data lineage ·

Data mapping · Consulting ·

Requirements gathering .

Business process analysis .

Project planning · Risk management

CERTIFICATION

Certified Business Analysis Professional (CBAP)

Completed the CBAP course by IIBA to expand my practical experience and knowledge of business analysis methods

SQL for Data Science Course

Completed an intensive SQL course run by Coursera, expanding my understanding of data manipulation for business intelligence purposes.

PASSIONS

Data Analysis

I have a passion for making sense of data, it's satisfying to turn raw data into actionable business insights.

Experienced Business Intelligence Analyst | Project Management | **SQL Expert**

SUMMARY

With over a decade's experience in business analysis and intelligence, I am adept at juggling multiple work items and understanding complex business processes. Notably, I led a business critical reporting project at Adobe that improved project timeline outcomes. My strengths lie in my analytical approach, proficiency in SQL and my experience in managing conflicting business needs.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Business Intelligence Analyst

2017 - 2021

Oracle

Redwood City, California

Lead on business intelligence projects and development of operational reports.

- Collaborated with IT and business teams to gather and analyse reporting requirements, leading to the successful implementation of a company-wide BI framework.
- Initiated and facilitated meetings and workshops to ensure all stakeholders are aligned and informed, leading to improved project timelines and outcomes.
- Implemented data mapping processes to understand the impact on the data model by source systems which led to increased efficiency in data integration.

Business Analyst

2013 - 2017

Adobe Systems

San Jose, California

Supported the implementation of business intelligence solutions and improvements.

- Communicated and documented the IT Impact for diverse operational projects, ensuring all changes are accurately communicated and understood.
- Managed and prioritised various work items effectively, ensuring project deadlines are
- Increased productivity by 25% by aligning conflicting needs and prioritising key projects.

Junior Business Analyst

2010 - 2013

HP Inc.

San Jose, California

Supported the development of business systems and operational procedures.

- Involved in key BI change projects, learning to combine IT and Business requirements to devise practical solutions.
- Contributed to user system testing and planning, reviewing and adjusting implementation strategies to better fit key operational outcomes.
- Identified IT vulnerabilities and established steps to mitigate risk, providing data security for critical projects.

EDUCATION

MSc Business Intelligence and Data Analytics

2008 - 2010

Stanford University

Stanford, California

BA Business Administration

2004 - 2008

University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, California

LANGUAGES

English Spanish Native Advanced